老实说  似乎短短几个星期
You know what? It seems like all of the sudden;
发生了那么多
so much has happened.
就是啊  罗斯要结婚了
I know. Ross is getting married.
菲比在...造人
Phoebe's making people.
-大家都在忙  -只有我们坐在这里
- Everybody's doing stuff. - We just sit here.
要是我死了
I mean if I die
我来过这里的唯一证据
the only way people would even know I was here,
就是这张椅子上的屁股印
would be by the ass print on this chair!
我们得做件大事  惊天动地的大事
Look, we have to do something. Okay? Something huge!
我们可以去爬珠穆朗玛峰
We could climb Mt. Everest.
不是落人笑柄  是惊天动地
No-no, not something stupid, something huge.
不  不  我看到一则录影带的广告
No, no. I saw an ad for this video,
每天都有人在爬  我们也可以爬
people climb that thing everyday! We could totally do that!
谁说不行  不过是爬山而已
Why not?! I mean it's just, it's just climbing!
-不过是陡峭了点  -是啊
- It's just steep! - Yeah.
我们就去爬珠穆朗玛峰
We're going to Everest!
在山顶上留屁股印一定很赞
Okay, it would be nice to leave an ass print on Everest!
你们在干嘛呢
What's up?
-我们要去爬珠穆朗玛峰  -没错  宝贝儿
- We're gonna climb Mt. Everest. - Yeah, baby!
真的吗  我详细查过
Really? I looked into that.
登珠峰要花六万块  而且可能会死
Yeah, but, I mean it costs like $60,000 and you know you can die.
你俩一定会死
And you would die.
我们可以去租珠穆朗玛峰的录影带
We could get that Everest video, though.
那样就不必冒生命危险了
Yeah, we could do that without risking our lives at all.
等到了录影带店
While we're at the video store,
知道我们还要租什么吗
you know what else we could rent?
《虎胆龙威》
Die Hard!
话说  我刚记起来
You konw what? I just remembered.
那盘录影带只能邮购
That Everest thing is only available through mail order.
-所以你们要留下来陪我咯  -是啊
- So you'll stay here and hang out with me? - Yeah.
不过总有一天
But I'll tell you something, one of these days
我们要拍拍屁股站起来
we'll get off our butts
再去租一次《虎胆龙威》
and rent Die Hard again!
决定了吗
So what did we decide?
请不请你的纳森叔叔
Does your Uncle Nathan get an invite or not?
天啊  没有人喜欢他
Oh, God! Nobody likes him.
他好小器  他绝不会飞去伦敦的
He's so cheap. He'd never fly to London in a million years.
好  请吧
Invite him!
我的字写得还可以吗
Did I do these neat enough?
挺不错的
Yeah, they're fine.
别人问起来  我们就说是本写的
If anyone asks, we'll just say Ben addressed them.
你还请了瑞秋
So you invited Rachel then?
对啊  干嘛不请
Sure, why not?
真的吗
Really?
如果邀请我的旧情人  我会觉得很别扭
I wouldn't be comfortable having any of my old lovers there.
你觉得我们不该请她吗
Wait, do you think, maybe we shouldn't invite her?
不  罗斯  我很喜欢瑞秋
Oh, no-no, Ross, you know I absolutely adore Rachel.
我只是...怕你会尴尬
It's just that I thought it might be awkward for you.
不过这完全由你来决定
But it's absolutely your decision.
-还要茶吗  -好
- More tea? - Sure.
伯爵茶行吗
Earl Grey?
好  你想请谁就请谁
Fine, invite whoever you want.
我不想单身了  好吗
I don't want to be single, okay?
我只想再婚
I just... I just want to be married again.
我还只想要一百万咧
And I just want a million dollars!
瑞秋
Rachel?
天啊  莫妮卡  谢天谢地
Oh God, Monica. Thank God!
各位  这是瑞秋  林肯高中的另一位幸存者
Everybody. This is Rachel. Another Lincoln High survivor.
这是我的朋友们  这是钱德勒
This is everybody. This is Chandler.
菲比
And Phoebe.
乔伊
And Joey.
-你记得我哥罗斯吗  -当然记得
- Do you remember my brother Ross? - Sure.
这事你可能不知道  念高中时...
You know you probably didn't know this, but back in high school...
我一直暗恋你
I had a major crush on you.
我知道
I knew.
是吗
You did?
我以为你只当我是莫妮卡的怪胎哥哥
I figured you just thought I was Monica's geeky older brother.
没错
I did.
你觉得...
Listen, do you think...
请别被我容易紧张的缺点
And try not to let my intense vulnerability
影响你的决定
become any kind of a factor here.
我改天可以约你出去吗
Would it be okay if I asked you out sometime, maybe?
可以啊
Yeah.
或许可以
Maybe.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  我说不定会约你
Okay, maybe I will.
我看到
See, I see
你会拥有一段火热恋情
big passion in your future.
-真的吗  -对
- Really? - I do.
罗斯  你真好
Ross, you're so great.
别做梦了
It's never gonna happen.
我想问个问题
I have a question.
其实不算是问题
Actually, it's not so much a question.
算是个疑惑
It's more of a general wondering...
...疑虑
...ment.
-什么事  -是这样
- Okay? - Okay.
其实我一直想要...
Well, for a while now, I've been wanting to...
对
Yes, yes.
-快看那只小猫咪啊  -没错
- Oh, look at the little cat! - That's right.
什么
What?
世界的顶端
Top of the world looking
俯瞅万物
Down on creation
我唯一能寻到的解释
And the only explanation I can find
你给我听着
Alright, listen, missy!
车在人在  车亡人亡
If you want this can't, you'll have to take me with it!
-你看到了吗  -太难以置信了
- Did you see that? - You were incredible!
全新的瑞秋诞生了  女士们先生们
A brand-new woman, ladies and gentlemen.
没有你我绝对办不到
I could not have done this without you.
好吧
Okay.
烘干机里还有衣服吗
More clothes in the dryer?
我没事
I'm fine.
你没资格说你对我有感觉
You had no right to tell me you had feelings for me.
什么
What?
知道你对我的感觉之前  我和朱莉过得很好
I was doing great with Julie before I found out about you.
知道你对我的感觉之前  我也过得很好
I was doing great too before I found out about you.
你以为看你们在一起我很好受吗
You think it's not easy for me to see you with Julie.
重点是我现在不需要这份感情
The point is I don't need this right now.
明白吗  已经来不及了
Okay? It's too late.
我和别人在一起了  我很幸福
I'm with somebody else. I'm happy.
木已成舟随风远去了
This ship has sailed!
好  你走啊  你爱找谁找谁去  罗斯
All right, fine! You go ahead and do that, all right, Ross?
我才不需要你这艘笨舟
I don't need your stupid ship!
-很好  -很好
- Good. - Good.
罗斯你知道吗  这是我生平第一次
Ross, do you realize this is the first time in my life
做自己喜欢的事情
I'm doing something I actually care about?
这是我生平第一次
This is the first time in my life
做我真正在行的事
I'm doing something that I'm actually good at.
要是你不懂...
If you don't get that...
不  我懂  我非常懂
No, I get that, okay, I get that big time.
我替你高兴
And I'm happy for you, but I'm tired of
但我不想再跟你的答录机交往了
having a relationship with your answering machine, okay?
我已经没辙了
I don't know what to do anymore.
我也是
Neither do I!
这跟马克有关吗
Is this about Mark?
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
-好  看来不是  -天啊
- Okay, it's not. - Oh, my god!
我不能为了同一件事跟你一吵再吵
I can't keep having this same fight over and over again, Ross.
你快把我逼疯了
You're making this too hard!
我逼你  那你要我怎么做
I'm making this too hard. Okay, what do you want me to do?
我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
也许我们应该分开
Look, maybe we should just take a break.
你说得对  我们先冷静一下
You're right. Let's take a break. Let's cool off.
去吃点酸奶冰淇淋什么的
Let's get some frozen yogurt or something.
不是
No.
我是说分手
A break from us.
干嘛这么着急啊
Do I know why are we rushing?
我昨晚提到的那个女朋友
The girlfriend I told you about last night.
她想跟我复合
She wants to get back together with me.
我找到了
I found it!
真是太好了
That's so great for you guys!
-祝你复合成功  -谢谢
- Good luck with your girlfriend. - Thank you.
瑞秋
Rachel!
-你听到留言了吗  -你来得正好
- You got my message? - You are right on time.
那么  我可以再当你的女朋友吗
So what do you say? Can I be your girlfriend again?
可以得不得了
Yes, you can very much.
你给我走  滚  快滚
I want you to leave. Get out of here! Just get out!
不  我想留下来谈一谈
No, I wanna stay. I want to talk about this.
好  她怎么样
All right, how was she?
-什么  -她活好吗
- What? - Was she good?
不要回答
Don't answer that!
来嘛  罗斯  你说你想谈
Come on Ross! You said you wanted to talk about it,
那就谈啊  她怎么样
let's talk about it!! How was she?
她...
She was...
-差劲  糟糕  -她很逊
- Awful! Horrible! - She was not good, not good.
什么都比不上你
Nothing compared to you.
她感觉很不同
She was different.
比我好吗
Good different?
没有人喜欢改变
Nobody likes change.
别再说了
Just stop!
你这么坦然认错
The way you owned up to everything.
证明你真的成长了不少
It's just showed me how much you've grown, you know?
我妈一直觉得我们无法复合
I mean, my mom never thought this would work out.
她说  狗改不了吃屎
She was all, "Once a cheater, always a cheater."
真希望没有这四个月的空白
I just wish we hadn't lost those four months.
但要是时间能让你认清错误
But if time was what you needed
那也不算浪费
just to gain a little perspective.
我们当时分手了
We were on a break!
你似乎真的很喜欢她
You seem to really like her.
我能怎么办  我们说好只在一起两周
What do I do? We agreed it'd be a two-week thing.
不做承诺
No commitment.
罗斯  那个女孩整晚都在
Ross, that girl just spent the entire evening
和你朋友聊天
talking to your friends
嚷着要听你的事
asking to hear stories about you
还看莫妮卡的相簿
looking through Monica's photo albums.
只想在一起两周才不会这样
You don't do that if you're just in it for two weeks.
是吗
You think?
她还有14个小时才去机场
You've got 14 hours until she has to be at the airport.
你却坐在走廊上
And you're sitting here in a hallway
陪一个香肠嘴的大龄啦啦队长
with a 28-year-old cheerleader with a fat lip.
-你说得对  -是啊
- You're right. - Yeah.
太棒了
This is so amazing!
我哥哥居然要去伦敦结婚
Can't believe my brother's getting married and in London!
好浪漫哦
It's just so romantic.
真聪明
Hey, pretty smart!
附面纸
Tissue paper.
参加婚礼当然会哭
You're at the wedding. You have to cry.
需要手帕吗  不了  我有喜帖
Handkerchief? No, I got my invitation.
太可爱了
Isn't this adorable?
罗斯让本写我的喜帖
Ross let Ben address mine.
大家好
Hello.
你收到罗斯的喜帖了吗
Did you get your invitation to Ross' wedding?
没有
No.
放心  我可以带一位亲友  给他点颜色瞧
Don't worry, I get to bring a guest. We'll show him.
好羡慕你们都能去
I'm so jealous you're all going.
我都不知道
I can't believe I never knew
怀孕七月以上不能坐飞机
you can't fly in your third trimester.
我也不知道
I didn't, either.
我知道
I knew that.
其实我也不知道  但你们的表情好逗
So I didn't know that. But you should see your faces.
你们在干嘛
Hey, guys. What's up?
没干嘛
Just hanging out.
这是什么  罗斯的喜帖
What's this? Ross' wedding invitation?
我们该藏的是那一张
Maybe that's the one we should have hidden.
不  伙计们  你们不必这样
No, you guys, come on. You don't have to do that.
我很替他高兴
I'm happy for him.
真的  我很...
I am. I really...
我会调整心态的
I'll work on it.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry honey.
不过你还是会去吧
You're going to come, though, aren't you?
我不知道
Honey, I don't know.
该不会是她不去  我们就不去了吧
This isn't one of those "If she doesn't come, we don't come"?
我已经买好机票了
Because I've already bought my ticket.
你要是不去才真的奇怪
You know what would be real weird? If you weren't there.
-你就考虑一下吧  -我会考虑的
- Just say you'll think about it. - I'll think about it.
-这是谁送的  -罗斯送的
- Who's this from? - That's Ross'.
天啊
Oh, my God!
他竟然记得
He remembered.
记得什么
Remembered what?
好几个月前  我们经过一家古董店
It was months ago. We were walking by this antique store.
我看到这个别针
and I saw this pin in the window,
对他说我奶奶有个一模一样的
and I told him that it was just like one my grandmother had
我小时候见过
when I was a little girl.
他居然记得
I can't believe he remembered!
他一定花了很多钱
This must've cost him a fortune.
他居然这么大方
I can't believe he did this.
罗斯嘛  他大学的时候
Come on, Ross? Remember back in college,
爱卡罗尔爱得死去活来
when he fell in love with Carol
就送了她一只超贵的水晶鸭
and got her that ridiculously expensive crystal duck?
你刚才说什么
What did you just say?
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
来自北京的457号班机已经抵达
Flight number 457 from Beijing now arriving.
天啊
Oh, my God!
我们是老同学
Well, Ross and I were in grad school together.
毕业后就没见过
But we haven't seen each other since then.
到了中国  你们猜是谁主持挖掘工作
I land in China. Guess who's in charge of the dig?
朱莉
Julie!
很棒吧
Isn't that great?
真是比蛋碎了一地  脖子被啐了还爽
Isn't that kick-you-in-the-crotch, spit-on-your-neck fantastic?
你真好
That is so sweet!
不
No.
不  你先挂
No, okay. No, you hang up.
不  你...  好
No, you... Okay.
好  一  二  三
Okay. One, two, three.
你也没挂
You didn't hang up, either!
她也没挂
She didn't hang up either.
不  你挂你挂
Okay, no. No, you hang up.
你
You!
罗斯  嗨
Ross, hi.
我是瑞秋
It's Rachel.
我只是打来告诉你一切都很好
I'm just calling to say that everything's fine.
我很替你和你的猫高兴
And I'm really happy for you and your cat.
显然  我已经不在乎你了
Obviously, I am over you.
我已经不在乎你了
I am over you.
而这  就是传说中的一刀两断
And that, my friend, is what they call closure.
瑞秋  我收到条你发的留言
Rach, I got a message from you.
天啊  罗斯  挂掉  把电话给我
Oh, my God! Ross, no, hang up the phone! Give me the phone.
电话给我  给我  给我
Give me the phone! Give me the phone! Give me the phone!
你不在乎我了
You're over me?
天啊
Oh, God.
你不在乎我了
You're over me?
你什么时候...
When were you...
在乎过我
under me?
基本上...
Basically...
最近...我...
lately, I've...
我对你有好感
I've sort of had feelings for you.
我得躺下
Okay, I need to lie down.
他跟朱莉分手了
He broke up with Julie!
过去抱她啊
Go hug her, for God's sakes!
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Really.
我一直都只想要你  瑞秋
It's always been you, Rach.
天啊
Oh, God.
抱歉  今晚我得工作
Listen, I'm sorry I had to work tonight.
没关系
That's okay.
你值得我等
You're worth the wait.
我不只是指今晚
And I don't just mean tonight.
天啊
Oh, God!
亲爱的
Honey.
没关系
That's okay.
不是  你把果汁盒压爆了
No, you just rolled over the juice box.
甘瑟  你没告诉瑞秋
Gunther, please tell me you didn't say anything to Rachel
我跟复印店女生的事吧
about me and the girl from the copy place?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不该说吗
Was I not supposed to?
是你要分手的
You're the one who ended it, remember?
因为我生你的气  不是因为我不爱你了
Yeah, because I was mad at you. Not because I stopped loving you.
-你还爱我吗  -不爱
- You still love me? - No.
什么意思  你想复合吗
What does this mean? Do you wanna, get back together?
不想  也许吧
No. Maybe.
我不知道
I don't know.
我只是觉得...
I just, I feel...
我居然会想跟你复合
I can't believe I even thought of getting back together with you.
我们彻底完了
We're so over!
无所谓
Fine by me!
顺便告诉你  别以为这种事很常见
And hey! Just so you know, it's not that common.
不是每个男人都能找到我这样的女朋友
It doesn't happen to every guy,
你损失大了
and it is a big deal.
我就知道
I knew it!
瑞秋来了  她是不是很美啊
Rachel's coming up. Doesrt she look pretty, Jack?
天啊
Oh, my God!
这是我们准备要去参加舞会的录像
You know what this is? This is us getting ready for the prom.
这种录影带就别看了
You know what, guys? We don't have to watch this.
当然要看
Yeah, we do!
拜托啦
Come on!
-拍一下莫妮卡  -镜头怎么拉远
- Get a shot of Monica. - How do you zoom out?
有了
There she is!
闭嘴  上镜头会多10磅
Shut up! The camera adds 10 pounds.
那到底是有几个镜头对着你
So how many cameras are actually on you?
爸  关掉啦
Dad, turn it off!
我关了
It is off.
对吧  罗斯
Right, Ross?
很帅哦  爆炸头
Looking good, Mr. Kotter!
我没舞伴不能去舞会  时间来不及了
I can't go to my prom without a date. I can't. It's too late.
要是你不去  我也不想去了
If you're not going, then I don't want to go either.
我有个好主意
I have a wonderful idea.
你带瑞秋去参加舞会
You should take Rachel to the prom.
看够了  关掉吧
You know what? I think we've seen enough. Let's turn it off.
-不要啦  我想看  -那我不看  行吧
- No, I want to see! - Fine, I'm not going to watch. Alright?
去吧  儿子
Come on, kid- Let's go-
你好帅
Are you handsome!
去让他们瞧瞧
Let's show them!
-好了  爸  -瑞秋  不管你准备好没有
- Okay, Dad. - Rachel, ready or not-
解救你的白马王...
Here comes your knight in shining...
不是吧
Oh, no.
再见
Bye.
奇普
Chip!
糟了
Oh, dear!
杰克  要怎么关掉
Jack, how do I turn this off?
你居然那样做了
I can't believe you did that.
我就...
Yeah, well...
看吧  他是她的龙虾
See? He's her lobster!
不会吧
No.
你真的不去吗
You're really not going?
我会很难面对
It's just going to be too hard.
毕竟...
You know, I mean...
是罗斯啊
...it's Ross.
我怎么能看着他结婚
How can I watch him get married?
这样最好  真的
It's just for the best. You know? It is.
而且总得有人陪菲比
Plus somebody's got to stay here with Phoebe.
到时她的肚子就会很大了
She's going to be pretty big by then.
她会需要别人绑鞋带
She'll need someone to help her tie her shoes.
在她要生的时候开车送她去医院
Drive her to the hospital if she goes into labor.
你没有车
You don't have a car.
驾照也过期了
And your license expired.
事情那么多  时间却那么少
There's so much to do, and I have so little time to do it in!
你们看
Check it out. Check this out.
上面提到  有个地方可以租到
It says here that there's a place you can go
所有博物馆的录影带
to rent videos of all the museums.
"几乎如同身历其境"
"It's almost as good as being there."
这样更棒  去博物馆还不能只穿内裤
It's better! You can't go to a museum in your underwear.
可以  但之后你会遭到封杀
You could, but probably just the one time.
我们可以去租景点录影带
I bet we could get videos of all the sights
在酒店房间放台录放影机  就能足不出户了
get a VCR in our hotel room and never have to go outside!
那一定要租《虎胆龙威》
If we do that, we've got to rent Die Hard-
我敢说英版一定很精彩
I bet the British version is good!